让我们考虑试图在人群中找到一张脸的问题，特别是
Let’s consider the problem of trying to find a face in a crowd and, in particular,
我想找到机器人Bender的脸。他在这里：他躲在Dalek后面
I want to find the face of the robot Bender. Here he is: he is hiding behind a Dalek and
站在夏娃旁边。因此，我们不得不扫描人群来找Bender，让我们来吧
standing next to Eve. So rather than us having to scan the crowd to find Bender, let’s
看看我们是否可以自动完成任务。我们将使用空间算子方法
see if we can automate the task. We are going to use the spatial operator approach
为了解决这个问题。我们要做的是每个输入窗口
in order to solve this problem. What we are going to do is for every input window we are
将它与模板图像进行比较，模板是图像，模式
going to compare it with a template image, the template being the image, the pattern
我们正在寻找，我们的功能现在是一个相似功能。我们要看
we are looking for and our function now is a similarity function. We are going to look
在图像左侧行进的特定输入窗口之间的相似性
at the similarity between the particular input window which marches across the image left
向右，从上到下。每个输入窗口，我们都要将它与我们的模板进行比较
to right, top to bottom. Every input window, we are going to compare it with our template
并且相似性得分将被放入输出图像中。所以模板会
and the similarity score is going to be placed into the output image. So the template will
作为Bender的面孔，我们将比较Bender在每一个方面的表情
be the face of Bender and we are going to compare the face of Bender at every single
整个场景的位置。那么我们如何比较两个图像，我们如何判断一个特定的图像
location across the scene. So how do we compare two images, how do we tell that a particular
输入窗口W看起来像Bender还是看起来不像Bender？
input window W looks like Bender or doesn’t look like Bender?
要做到这一点，我们需要一个图像相似性度量，最简单的一个称为总和
To do this we need an image similarity measure and the simplest one is called the sum of
绝对差异，有时缩写为SAD或sad（），而且我们非常简单地采用了
absolute differences, sometimes abbreviated to SAD or sad() and quite simply we take the
我们试图比较的两个图像中相应像素之间的差异。
difference between the corresponding pixels in the two images that we are trying to compare.
当然，它们必须是相同的大小，取其绝对值并总结。因此，如果
Of course, they must be the same size, take their absolute value and sum it up. So if
图像相同，相似性度量的值为0.如果它们不相似，
the images are identical, the similarity measure will have a value of 0. If they are dissimilar,
S的值大于0.所以0表示完美匹配;一个大的价值意味着一个不太完美
S will have a value greater than 0. So 0 means perfect match; a big value means a less perfect
比赛。一个非常类似的方法是操作符调用ssd（），平方差的和，和
match. A quite similar approach is the operator called ssd(), sum of square differences, and
而不是使用绝对值操作，我们采取正方形的总和。
instead of using the absolute value operation we are taking the sum of the squares.
另一个衡量标准是零均值归一化互相关，通常缩写为
Another measure is the zero - mean normalised cross correlation, commonly abbreviated to
ZNCC（）。它看起来要复杂得多，但它比这两个简单有一些优点
zncc(). It looks much more complicated, but it has some advantages over the two simple
以上措施。zncc（）度量从-1到+1变化。+1表示图像是
measures above. The zncc() measure varies from -1 to +1. +1 means that the images are
相同和-1表示一个图像是另一个图像的负像。0意味着
identical and -1 means that one image is the negative of the other one. 0 means that the
两幅图像的相关性不是很好。通常，考虑高于0.8的值
two images are not very well correlated. Typically, a value above 0.8 is considered
是一个合理的比赛。在这里，我们重新审视原始拼图，Bender突出显示。
to be a reasonable match. Here we revisit the original puzzle and there is Bender highlighted.
所以我们首先需要创建模板，所以在这里我将Bender切碎了，
So we first of all need to create the template, so here I have chopped Bender out of the scene,
所以它主要是本德尔和他的一些邻居。
so it is mostly Bender and a few of his neighbours as well.
然后我要做的是使用类似Photoshop的程序来删除所有的
And then what I am going to do is to use a Photoshop-like program to remove all of the
那个场景中没有Bender的机器人。我将尽可能多地放大
robots in that scene that are not Bender. I am going to zoom in as much as I can on
他的头部和所有其他我不感兴趣的机器人变黑了。所以这个
his head and blacken out all of the other robots that I am not interested in. So this
是模板，这是我要在图像中寻找的模式。
is the template, this is the pattern that I am going to go looking for in the image.
我要做的第一件事是将人群场景加载到工作空间变量中
The first thing I am going to do is load the crowd scene into a workspace variable which
我打电话给人群。我打算从文件wheres_walle.png加载它，它是一个
I am going to call crowd. I am going to load it from the file wheres_walle.png, it is a
PNG格式文件。我想将彩色图像转换为灰度，我想转换
PNG format file. I want to convert the colour image to grey scale and I want to convert
所有像素都是双精度值。也就是说，它们介于0和1之间
all the pixels to double precision values. That is, they lie between 0 and 1 and then
让我们展示一下。
let’s display that.
在那里我们看到人群场景，接下来我将加载机器人Bender的图像
And there we see the crowd scene, next I am going to load an image of the robot Bender
那也是PNG文件;要将其转换为双倍精度，我已加载
and that is in a PNG file also; going to convert that to double precision and I have loaded
进入工作区变量Bender。我们可以看到它是一个非常小的图像;它
that into the workspace variable Bender. We can see that it is a very small image; it
只有55行像素和41列像素。让我们在新窗口中显示。
has only got 55 rows of pixels and 41 columns of pixels. Let’s display that in a new window.
那是我们的模板。所以问题来了
And that is our template. So the problem to
手就是在每个可能的位置寻找特定的模板模式
hand is to look for that particular template pattern in every possible location in the
输入图像。所以这是一个非常大的搜索问题。要做到这一点，我将使用
input image. So this is a really big searching problem. To do that I am going to use the
工具箱函数称为相似性，我传递模板Bender的图像
tool box function called isimilarity and I pass in the image of Bender, the template
我们正在寻找，我正在寻找模板的场景和最后一个
that we are looking for, the scene in which I am searching for the template and the last
论证是相似性度量-我们刚刚讨论了相似性度量-我就是
argument is the similarity measure — we just talked about similarity measures — and I am
要使用zncc度量，零均值归一化互相关，这可能是Rolls
going to use the zncc measure, zero mean normalise cross correlation, which is perhaps the Rolls
罗伊斯的图像相似性测量，我将在我相当不错的计算
Royce of image similarity measures, and I am going to compute that on my rather nice
笔记本电脑。这个计算需要大约90秒，所以我们将跳过
laptop. This calculation takes about 90 something seconds so we are going to skip through to
结束。太好了，我们完成了。所以我们计算了变量S.它是一个大矩阵，我们
the end. Great, we are done. So we have computed the variable S. It is a large matrix and we
可以认为它是一个图像，并将其显示为这样，这是一个相似图像。
can consider it to be an image and display it as such and this is a similarity image.
现在我们在这里有这个相似性度量，所以让我们点击几点
Now what we have here is this similarity measure, so let’s just click around in a few points
我们可以看到，我点击的这些像素的相似度非常低
and we can see that these pixels that I am clicking on have got quite low similarity
测量。这意味着我点击模板的地方根本不适合。
measure. It means that where I have clicked the template is not at all a good fit.
在这里，我们可以看到一些更大的相似值，0.44,0.47。
Down here we can see some similarity values that are a little bit bigger, 0.44, 0.47.
最大值相似度为1.因此，在此位置可能是模板
The maximum value similarity is 1. So at this location it is possible that the template
存在，但它不是一个奇妙的契合。我们可以看到一些很暗的地方
exists but it is not a marvellous fit. We can see some places that are quite dark where
它肯定是非常差的合适。实际上，这是一种消极的相似性度量。但在某个地方
it is certainly is very poor fit. In fact it is a negative similarity measure. But somewhere
在这里会有一些非常明亮的像素，代表模板最适合的位置。
in here there will be some very bright pixels which represent where the template fits best.
所以这是一个非常大的矩阵：这里有近百万个数字和什么
So this is a very large matrix: there’s almost a million numbers in here and what
我们要做的是找到这个矩阵中最大的数字。
we have to do is to find the biggest number within this matrix.
现在我们有一个工具箱功能，它可以为我们这样做，它就像这样使用。
Now we have a tool box function which can do that for us and it’s used like this.
所以它有两个输出变量，我会在一瞬间解释它们。
So it has got two output variables and I will explain them in just a moment.
该函数称为peak2，我们传入相似图像。传递参数
The function is called peak2 and we pass in the similarity image. Pass in the argument
一个说我们想要找到最亮的像素，即最亮的像素
one which is saying that we want to find the brightest pixel, that is, the brightest pixel
相对于距离它一个像素的所有像素。所以它就像，它是
with respect to all of the pixels who are one pixel away from it. So it is like, it’s
在一个非常本地的区域内最明亮的，让我们要求五个最亮的山峰
the brightest within a very local region and let’s ask for the five brightest peaks in
降序排列。所以这是最亮的像素，第二个最亮的像素等等。
descending order. So that’s the brightest pixel, the second brightest pixel and so on.
花一点时间来计算;我们看到的是我们计算了两个输出变量，
Takes a moment to compute; and what we see is we have computed two output variables,
现在是第一个，我们称之为MX或者最大的那个是最亮的像素的值
now the first one, the one we call MX or maximum is the value of that brightest pixel and the
矩阵P中的对应列是该最亮像素的坐标。
corresponding column in the matrix P is the coordinate of that brightest pixel.
所以它所说的是在相似图像中它具有最大的相似性
So what it is saying is within that similarity image the greatest similarity that it has
找到的值为0.6107，它出现在U坐标331和V坐标处
found has got a value of 0.6107 and it occurs at a U coordinate of 331 and a V coordinate
第二个最佳拟合的相似度为0.5580，我们可以看到它的坐标，第三个
of 364. The second best fit has got a similarity of 0.5580 and we can see its coordinate, third
最佳合身，第四最佳合身，第五最佳合身等。
best fit, fourth best fit, fifth best fit and so on.
因此，为了使其可视化，我们可以做的是选择原始图像和什么
So in order to visualise that, what we can do is to select the original image and what
我要做的是在这张图片上绘制一些圆圈，表明我们在哪里发现这些圆圈
I am going to do is to plot some circles on this image that indicate where we found these
很合适。所以这是对这个函数的很多论据，但基本上就是说
good fits. So this is rather a lot of arguments to this function, but basically it is saying
绘制一个半径为30像素的圆，并绘制其中每个圆的一个圆
plot a circle of radius 30 pixels and plot one of these circles for every column in the
矩阵P.所以它将绘制5个圆圈。我希望圆圈是蓝色的。一世
matrix P. So it is going to plot 5 circles. I want the circles to be coloured blue. I
希望它们是半透明的，所以我们将这些圆的alpha值设置为0.3，这就是
want them to be translucent, so we set the alpha value for these circles to 0.3, which
意味着它们是通过圆圈看到的，并且它们没有任何边缘颜色
means that they are see through circles and that they do not have any edge colour and
在这里，我们认为机器人Bender所在的每个地方都有一个蓝色圆圈。
here we go, there is a blue circle on every place where we think the robot Bender is.
现在让我们也指出选择的等级;另一个相当复杂的功能
Now let’s also indicate the rank of the selections; another rather complex function
打电话，但它基本上说每个点P，我想要一个序号
call, but it’s basically saying for every point P, I want to put a sequential number
在粗体字体文字大小36，黄色书写，我们去，所以我们可以看到第一个最好的
in a bold font text size 36, in yellow writing and here we go, so we can see the first best
适合，第二最佳，第三，第四和第五，我们可以看到蓝色圆圈与
fit, second best fit, third, fourth and fifth and we can see that the blue circle with the
旁边的第一个确实是机器人本德......我们正在仔细观察;
number one next to it is indeed the robot Bender … we are looking closely enough;
我们可以看到班德在那里的幸福面孔。
we can see Bender’s happy face there.
我们将在我们找到机器人弯曲机的位置周围提取人群场景的区域。
We are going to extract a region of the crowd scene around where we located the robot Bender.
我们将通过使用iroi函数，感兴趣区域函数来实现。
We are going to do that by using the iroi function, the region of interest function.
并传递整个图像，人群图像，我们将通过坐标
And to pass in the entire image, the crowd image, we are going to pass in the coordinate
模板具有最佳匹配的点，即矩阵的第一列
of the point where the template had the best match, that is, the first column of the matrix
P.矩阵P的每列表示图像中拟合模板的点
P. Each column of the matrix P represents a point in the image where the template fitted
无论是第一好，第二好等等。所以第一列就是了
either first best, second best and so on. So the first column is the point where the
模板拟合最好，我们将提取一个50像素正方形的区域
template fitted the best and we are going to extract a region which is 50 pixels square
所以在这里我们看到了人群场景的区域，我们在那里发现了机器人Bender和
and so here we see the region of the crowd scene where we found the robot Bender and
在右边，我们看到了Bender的模板。我们可以看到这些地区并不完全
on the right we see the template of Bender. We can see that these regions are not quite
相同。但是我们在左边显示了模板适合的像素图案
the same. But we are showing on the left a pattern of pixels where the template fitted
最好的。所以我所做的就是拿原版
the best. So what I have done is to take the original
人群场景的图像，我已经切出了一堆像Bender的脸的像素
image of the crowd scene and I have cut out a bunch of pixels which has Bender’s face
在其中，我已经进入Photoshop并且我已经将一些背景涂黑了
in it, I have gone into Photoshop and I have blacked out some of the background which is
不相关-他们不是Bender的一部分，他们实际上是机器人的一部分
not relevant — they are not part of Bender, they are actually part of the robots around
Bender-这就是我找到模板的方式。因此，如果我将此模板应用于其他模板
Bender — and that is how I found the template. So if I applied this template to a different
机器人人群场景也许，在人群中，班德没有雪茄;也许
robot crowd scene and perhaps, in that crowd scene, Bender didn’t have a cigar; perhaps
他正朝另一个方向看;也许他离镜头越来越近了
he was looking in another direction; perhaps he was closer to the camera and appeared to
更大，或者他离得更远，看起来更小。然后是一个简单的模板
be bigger, or he was further away and appeared to be smaller. Then a simple-minded template
像这样的匹配技术不会特别好用。
matching technique like this is not going to work particularly well.